<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-05T10:36:21-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Eddie Hinkle</title><subtitle>Husband of 1, Father of 2. Director of UX at ThreatConnect. Two Dads Co-Host. Thoughts are mine. ✝️</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Advent Week 1: Hope</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/1/article/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advent Week 1: Hope" /><published>2020-12-05T10:08:40-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-05T10:08:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/1/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/12/05/1/article/">&lt;p&gt;Growing up, we had Advent candles. There are 5 candles in a set, one that gets lit each Sunday leading up to Christmas, and then the final, fifth candle that gets lit on Christmas Eve or Day. Each candle represents a “theme” of Advent. As we’ve been doing it this year, I’ve been thinking about and reflecting on the theme of each week. Hope is a fitting theme to start the Advent season with considering everything that has happened in 2020. Here are some thoughts I’d had on Hope this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ashley and I really enjoyed the Hunger Games series. We watched each movie together and eventually purchased them all to continue to watch. Two things have stuck with us outside the context of those movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Catching Fire, the second Hunger Games movie, Katniss Everdeen’s coach looks at her just before she walks into a particular hard, particularly bad contest and gives her one reminder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Remember who the real enemy is”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s powerful in that moment, because Katniss is about to enter a battlefield where 22 other people want to and need to kill her in order for themselves to survive. But the key to remember is that the other 22 people didn’t choose to be there. They are slaves in the same way that she is. Instead, the real enemy is President Snow, the tyrant ruler of their country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way, it is common for us to determine that someone or something around us is the enemy. Our boss, our co-workers, our spouse, our kids, our neighbor, even our government. Those can be the case, they may be harming us intentionally or not, which does make them a real threat and cause for concern. Katniss couldn’t just ignore the fact that 22 people wanted her dead. But the odds of her against 22 people were overwhelming, so her focus had to be on who the real enemy was. In the same way, life can be overwhelming and it can be hard to know how we can deal with it. I get overwhelmed a lot, especially this year. Having 2 kids under 2 during a global pandemic has not been an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve been reflecting on hope, I’ve been asking myself, how do I have hope this year? What do I tell Ashley? What do I tell others? If Hope is a foundational element of the Advent season and thus my faith, there has to be an answer. Today, after taking my cat to the vet for her allergy shot, I was listening to music and the song “Never Fail” by Anthony Evans came on. The following words popped out to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Lord is with us&lt;br /&gt;
The Lord is with us&lt;br /&gt;
Our God is for us&lt;br /&gt;
He will never fail&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Our Hope is revived&lt;br /&gt;
In your presence&lt;br /&gt;
As we sing to you&lt;br /&gt;
Your word comes alive &lt;br /&gt;
In your presence&lt;br /&gt;
As we trust in you&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Our faith cannot be shaken&lt;br /&gt;
Nothing can separate us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started coming together in my mind. There are a lot of enemies and obstacles in 2020, that have overwhelmed and caused issues in my life. A biological virus, my own inabilities and emotional struggles, challenges of raising children, our president, even the realization of the lack of friends surrounding us. While each of these things have impacted my life as a threat, either emotional, influentially or physically. But none of them is the ultimate enemy (although a global pandemic comes close). “Remember who the real enemy is”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental challenge and enemy in life is sin and death. (I told you the virus got close. Haha). Often during years like this people ask “Is this the way life was meant to be?” and the answer is no. This isn’t the way life was meant to be. God created everything in life perfect. We deal with a shadow of the life that God intended for us because sin and death entered the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we deal with that? How do we restore life the way it was meant to be? Lots of peope think they have the answers. Churches, businesses, religions and governments all over the world will tell you life will be what you want it to be “if”. “If” the right person gets elected. “If” you give your money to the church. “If” you give your life to God. “If” you buy this thing, or “if” you take these pills. Everything will be the way its supposed to be. But it’s not. There is no way to make life the way it was meant to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where is the hope? “The Lord is with us, Our God is for us”. Echoes the words in Anthony Evans song. “Our faith cannot be shaken. Nothing can separate us”. This life is hard, and the only thing that can change is that we are not alone. We have &lt;strong&gt;hope&lt;/strong&gt; because God is with us. We have &lt;strong&gt;hope&lt;/strong&gt; because Jesus was born sometime around 2000 years ago, and it marked two things. That we are not alone, and that our enemy will be defeated. I don’t want to go too much into the last one because that’s a different advent theme I want to think about later. But the first part of hope comes from the fact that no matter what we go through, we don’t go through it alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the other things Ashley and I have taken from the Hunger Games. The mockingjay call. In the first movie, Katniss forged an alliance with a girl, Rue. They realized that if they whistled like birds that the birds would echo their calls and they could communicate to each other that they were safe. When Rue dies, Katniss holds up a three finger salute to the camera. It is traditionally used in her district as a funeral sign. But after that, throughout the movies people will hold up the three finger salute to show they are joining Katniss in the rebellion. I’ve found that as you watch it throughout the movies it’s a sign that says “I see you, I’m with you. You’re not alone”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jokingly, over time when Ashley or I found ourselves in a hard place, we would hold up the three finger salute and do the mockingjay bird call, to jokingly reassure each other, “I’m with you” commonly if we are about to go do different things and can’t be together. Today amid the pandemic as we are juggling working, taking care of kids and trying to keep our mental sanity…it’s a small, silly gesture, but it’s an important one. It’s a gesture of hope. I’m with you. I’ll be back for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge symbol of hope is when people who follow Jesus can gather around each other and say “I’m with you”. Churches today often completely fail at this aspect. Whether in a church, small group, Bible study or just friends. One of the most practical things that can bring hope in dark times is saying I’m with you. We’re in this together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally as I mentioned above, we use it as a sign that, “I’ll be back for you. You are important to me.” And that’s the ultimate hope of the Advent season. Jesus was born. He died. He came back to life. But he also left and said he’d be back for us. Advent is a time of hope because it’s a time to remember that things aren’t how they should be, we’re not alone, and he’ll be back for us. When he does, everything will be as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="advent" /><category term="faith" /><summary type="html">Growing up, we had Advent candles. There are 5 candles in a set, one that gets lit each Sunday leading up to Christmas, and then the final, fifth candle that gets lit on Christmas Eve or Day. Each candle represents a “theme” of Advent. As we’ve been doing it this year, I’ve been thinking about and reflecting on the theme of each week. Hope is a fitting theme to start the Advent season with considering everything that has happened in 2020. Here are some thoughts I’d had on Hope this week.</summary></entry></feed>